Guide to the Samuel Bourne photographs, circa 1861-circa 1889 RL.00130
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographic prints, circa 1861-circa 1889; 1; 546 prints 21 boxes
  - Srinuggur; Poplar Avenue from the middle, circa 1864-1865; 8 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0801a)
    Original negative number: 801a
  - Srinuggur; Avenue of Chunars in the Nasib Bagh, circa 1864; 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0803)
    Original negative number: 803
  - Srinuggur; View from the Nautch Bungalow, Shalimar, circa 1864; 9 3/8 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0805)
    Original negative number: 805
  - Srinuggur; A Group of Kashmir Females, circa 1864-1865; 9 1/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 1, Print RL-00130-P-0809)
    From Photograph Album 1: Farther India, page 41. Title on print reads "Kashmir Women."
    Original negative number: 809
  - Srinuggur; A Merchant's House on the Marqual Canal, circa 1864; 9 1/4 x 11 1/8 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0814)
    Original negative number: 814
  - Srinuggur; A Bridge on the Marqual Canal, circa 1864-1865; 8 1/4 x 11 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-0815)
    Unmounted print. Title and number assigned by dealer from unknown source.
    Original negative number: 815
  - Srinuggur; The Tukht-i-Soliman, circa 1864; 9 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0817)
    Original negative number: 817
  - Srinuggur; from the Tukht Hill, circa 1864-1865; 9 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 14, Print RL-00130-P-0818-1)
    Original negative number: 818
  - Srinuggur; from the Tukht Hill, circa 1864-1865; 9 1/4 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 15, Print RL-00130-P-0818-2)
  - Srinuggur; City view from Safoola Bab's House, circa 1864-1865; 9 1/4 x 11 inches (Box 14, Print RL-00130-P-0819)
    Original negative number: 819
  - Bridge near Srinuggur, built by Akbar, circa 1864; 9 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0822)
    Original negative number: 822
  - Srinuggur; A View on the Canal, circa 1864-1865; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 14, Print RL-00130-P-0825-1)
    Handwritten caption on mount reads "The Dhal Canal. Serinugger." Number as written on print, 825a, does not show up on currently known Bourne & Shepherd list, but image is the same as number 825 in box 15. "Prize photograph, 1865" (note in studio list in Rayner's book on Bourne).
    Original negative number: 825
  - Srinuggur; A View on the Canal, circa 1864-1865; 9 5/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 15, Print RL-00130-P-0825-2)
    Unmounted print. "Prize photograph, 1865" (note in studio list in Rayner's book on Bourne).
  - Srinuggur; Chunars overhanging the Dhul Canal, circa 1864-1865; 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 15, Print RL-00130-P-0833)
    Original negative number: 833
  - Srinuggur; The Maharajah's Palace, circa 1864-1865; 4 1/4 X 7 3/4 inches (Box 15, Print RL-00130-P-0837)
    Date on mount, 1865.
    Original negative number: 837
  - Srinuggur; Foliage on the Dhul Canal, circa 1864-1865; 4 1/8 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0842)
    Original negative number: 842
  - Srinuggur; Chunar Bagh Reach, on the Dhul Canal, circa 1864-1865; 4 1/8 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0844)
    Original negative number: 844
  - Cascades on the Scinde River, 1864; 4 1/8 x 3 3/4 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0899)
    Original negative number: 899
  - Glaciers in the Scinde Valley, 1864; 11 1/2 9 3/8 inches (Box 26, Print RL-00130-P-0905)
    Original negative number: 905
  - Lake Manusbul; Evening, circa 1865-1866; 4 1/8 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0943)
    Caption on print: "Manus Bull, evening."
    Original negative number: 943
  - Lake Manusbul; View from Hill Above Encamping Ground, circa 1865-1866; 4 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0946)
    Caption on print: "Manus Bull, from Hill above encamping ground."
    Original negative number: 946
  - Murree; View from Pindee Point, circa 1865-1866; 4 1/4 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0963)
    Original negative number: 963
  - Murree; The East End, from the Hill above the Church, circa 1865-1866; 3 7/8 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0968)
    Original negative number: 968
  - Manusbul; From head of Lake, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0970)
    Original negative number: 970
  - Lake Manusbul; From Encamping Ground, circa 1865-1866; 9 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0971)
    Original negative number: 971
  - The Scinde Valley; The Village of Gugangair, circa 1864; 9 1/4 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0976)
    Original negative number: 976
  - The Scinde Valley; A View near Gugangair, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0977)
    Original negative number: 977
  - The Scinde Valley below Sonamurg, circa 1864; 9 1/4 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0978)
    Original negative number: 978
  - Cascades on the Scinde Valley, circa 1864; 9 1/4 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0980)
    Original negative number: 980
  - The Village of Sonamurg, circa 1864; 10 7/8 x 9 5/8 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0981)
    Original negative number: 981
    Provenance: From a presentation album of Samuel Bourne photographs dated March 26th, 1868. Image may show Bourne's own camp and darkroom tent. Unmounted.
  - Glaciers near Sonamurg, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0984)
    Original negative number: 984
  - A View in the Scinde Valley, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0985)
    Original negative number: 985
  - Cascades on the Scinde River, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 14, Print RL-00130-P-0988)
    Title caption on print mount is "The Scinde Valley." No negative number shows on print; number 988 penciled in on mount; another dealer assigns it 899, Cascades on the Scinde River. Small tear at top center.
    Original negative number: 988
  - A View in the Zojji-La Pass, circa 1864; 11 1/4 x 9 1/2 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-0990)
    Original negative number: 990
  - Sunset on Lake Manusbul, circa 1865-1866; 8 1/8 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-0993)
    Original negative number: 993
  - Murree; View from Pindee Point, circa 1864; 9 x 11 1/8 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-1002)
    Original negative number: 1002
    Provenance: From a presentation album of Samuel Bourne photographs dated March 26th, 1868. Murree, originally Mari, is the ancient site of a shrine and village in what is now known as Pakistan. A hill-station was established there by the British in the 1850s. Unmounted.
  - Murree; View from Oak Knoll, circa 1864; 9 3/8 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-1003)
    Original negative number: 1003
    Provenance: From a presentation album of Samuel Bourne photographs dated March 26th, 1868. View of Catholic church. Unmounted.
  - Murree; View above the Hotel, circa 1864; 9 1/4 x 11 1/8 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-1004)
    Original negative number: 1004
    Provenance: From a presentation album of Samuel Bourne photographs dated March 26th, 1868. Another view of Catholic church. Unmounted.
  - Murree; View from the Barracks, circa 1864; 9 1/8 x 11 1/8 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-1005)
    Original negative number: 1005
  - Murree; A Glimpse through the Forest, circa 1865-1866; 11 5/8 x 9 1/2 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1010)
    Original negative number: 1010
  - Lucknow; Oudh Exhibition and surrounding scenery, circa 1865-1866; 4 1/4 X 7 3/4 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1014)
    Original negative number: 1014
  - Lucknow; Chutter Munzil, etc. general view, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1018-1)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 58. The number 1018 is inscribed on upper corner of album page.
    Original negative number: 1018
  - Lucknow; Chutter Munzil, general view, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1018-2)
    Unmounted print. No studio negative number appears, but is found on another image in the collection and online.
  - Lucknow; Chutter Munzil, near view, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1019)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 59.
    Original negative number: 1019
  - Lucknow; Bailey Guard, Residency etc., General View, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1025)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 55.
    Original negative number: 1025
  - Lucknow; Bailey Guard Gate, circa 1865-1866; 8 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-1027)
    Mounted on black paper cut to size of print.
    Original negative number: 1027
  - Lucknow; Ruins of the Residency, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1028)
    Original negative number: 1028
  - Lucknow; The Kaiser Bagh, circa 1865-1866; 4 1/4 X 7 3/4 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1035)
    Original negative number: 1035
  - Lucknow; The Kaiser Bagh, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-1036)
    Original negative number: 1036
  - Lucknow; View in the Kaiser Bagh, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1037)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 60.
    Original negative number: 1037
  - Lucknow; Vinery and Buildings in the Kaiser Bagh, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1038)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 61.
    Original negative number: 1038
  - Lucknow; The Mermaid Gate, Kaiser Bagh, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1041)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 62.
    Original negative number: 1041
  - Lucknow; East Gate of the Kaiser Bagh, from the garden, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1042)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 64.
    Original negative number: 1042
  - Lucknow; La Martiniere, from the Garden, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1047)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 70.
    Original negative number: 1047
  - Lucknow; The Roumi Darwaza in the Fort, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1048)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 65.
    Original negative number: 1048
  - Lucknow; Tomb of Zenab Aliya in the Hooseinabad Emambara, circa 1865-1866; 8 5/8 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1049)
    Original negative number: 1049
  - Lucknow; Buildings in the Garden of the Hooseinabad Emambara, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1050)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 68.
    Original negative number: 1050
  - Lucknow; View from the Terrace of the Hooseinabad Emambara, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1051)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 67.
    Original negative number: 1051
  - Lucknow; Great Emambara and Mosque, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1052)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 66.
    Original negative number: 1052
  - Lucknow; General View from Fort, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1053)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 57. Captioned in album as "Lucknow; Wingfield Park."
    Original negative number: 1053
  - Lucknow; View from the Terrace of the Hooseinabad Emambara, circa 1865-1866; 4 1/4 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 5, Print RL-00130-P-1056)
    Original negative number: 1056
  - Lucknow; Chutter Munzil, from the South, circa 1865-1866; 4 1/4 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1063)
    Unmounted print. Number assigned from caption on back of print.
    Original negative number: 1063
  - Lucknow; The Graves of Neil Lawrence etc, in the Cemetery, circa 1865-1866; 8 1/8 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1064)
    Original negative number: 1064
  - Lucknow; The Residency, from the North West, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1065)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 54.
    Original negative number: 1065
  - Lucknow; The Gate and Garden of the Hooseinabad Emambara, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1068)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 69.
    Original negative number: 1068
  - Agra; The Gate of the Taj, circa 1865-1866; 8 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1074)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 2. Print number taken from J. Paul Getty Museum uncropped print, which has Bourne 1074 inscribed on it.
    Original negative number: 1074
  - Agra; The Gate of the Taj, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1074)
  - Agra; The Taj and Garden, from the Entrance Gate, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1075)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 3.
    Original negative number: 1075
  - Agra; The Taj, from the Fountain, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1077)
    Original negative number: 1077
  - Agra; The Taj, from the River, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1078-1)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 4. Page caption reads "Agra; Taj from the Jumna."
    Original negative number: 1078
  - Agra; The Taj, from the River, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1078-2)
  - Agra; The Taj from the South, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1079)
    Original negative number: 1079
  - Agra; The Taj, from the corner of the Quadrangle, circa 1865-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1080)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 1.
    Original negative number: 1080
  - Agra; Christ Church from the East, circa 1865-1866; 4 1/4 x 3 5/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1098)
    Original negative number: 1098
  - Golas (Salt Makers), circa 1863-1866; 6 1/2 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1102)
    Printed on mount: "Golahs. Low Caste Hindoo Tribe. Rajpootana. 351." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text on both sides, concerning this ethnic group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1102
  - Rungrazes (Dyers), circa 1863-1866; 5 3/8 x 7 3/4 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1103)
    Printed on mount: "Dyers. Mahomedans. Delhi. 183." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text on both sides, concerning this ethnic group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1103
  - Gold Lace Makers, circa 1863-1866; 5 1/2 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1104)
    Printed on mount: "Zunlozis. Gold Lace Weavers. Mussulmans. Delhi. 187." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text on both sides, concerning this ethnic group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1104
  - Mairwaries (Cloth-Merchants), circa 1863-1866; 7 1/2 x 9 1/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1105)
    Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, "A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.")
    Original negative number: 1105
  - Sadhus (Fakeers), circa 1863-1866; 6 x 7 3/8 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1108)
    Printed on mount: "Sadhs. Hindoo Sect. Rajpootana. 348." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text concerning this ethnic group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1108
  - Mohamedans, circa 1863-1866; 7 x 9 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1109)
    Unmounted print. Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.)
    Original negative number: 1109
  - Groups of Bankers, circa 1863-1866; 7 1/2 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1110)
    Unmounted print. Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.) Mounted on black paper only slightly larger than print.
    Original negative number: 1110
  - Moulvies, circa 1863-1866; 5 1/2 x 7 3/4 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1111)
    Printed on mount: "Moulvees. Mussulman Lawyers. Delhi. 198." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text concerning this ethnic group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.)
    Original negative number: 1111
  - Jats, circa 1863-1866; 6 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1114)
    Printed on mount: "Jats. Hindoos. Delhi. 192." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text concerning this ethnic group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.)
    Original negative number: 1114
  - Hermaphrodites, circa 1863-1866; 7 1/4 x 8 3/4 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1115)
    Original negative number: 1115
  - Jat Zeminders, circa 1863-1866; 5 1/8 x 7 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1116)
    Printed on mount: "Jat Zeminders. Hindoos. Rajpootana. 344." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text concerning this group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1116
  - Jat Sirdars (Bhurtpore), circa 1863-1866; 7 3/8 x 9 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1118)
    Unmounted print. Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.)
    Original negative number: 1118
  - Lodas (Cultivators), circa 1863-1866; 6 1/4 x 8 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1119)
    Unmounted print. Dealer-assigned number and title, from unknown source. Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.)
    Original negative number: 1119
  - Rajpoots, circa 1863-1866; 6 1/2 x 6 5/8 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1120)
    Printed on mount: "Rajpoots. Hindoos. Delhi. 199." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text concerning this group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1120
  - Banya's Shop, circa 1863-1866; 7 3/8 x 9 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1121)
    Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1121
  - Sansies (A Tribe of thieves and shoplifters) Delhi District, circa 1863-1866; 8 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1122)
    Original negative number: 1122
  - Shrofs (Money changers), circa 1863-1866; 7 1/2 x 6 1/2 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1124)
    On smaller mount. Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1124
  - Embroiderer, circa 1863-1866; 6 1/2 x 4 3/4 inches (Box 16, Print RL-00130-P-1125)
    Printed on mount: "Scarf Maker. Mussulman. Delhi. 188." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text concerning this group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who reportedly created many of the ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1125
  - An Indian Carriage and Pair, circa 1863-1866; 7 1/4 x 9 1/4 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1128)
    Original negative number: 1128
  - Gujur Sirdars (Bhurtpore District), circa 1863-1866; 5 3/4 x 7 1/2 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1129)
    Printed on mount: "Goojur Sirdars. Hindoos. Rajpootana. 345." Accompanied by leaf of same size, with text concerning this ethnic group. Used in People of India (8 vols., 1868-1875). Numbers 1101 to circa 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs)
    Original negative number: 1129
  - A Thibetan Lama from Lassa, circa 1863-1866; 7 1/4 x 8 5/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1132A)
    Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.)
    Original negative number: 1132A
  - A Group of Thibetans, circa 1863-1866; 6 7/8 x 9 1/4 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1132B)
    Captioned on mount as "Thibetans." Numbers 1101 to about 1132 are probably the work of Charles Shepherd, who created many of the studio's ethnic portraits. (Source: Rayner, A Catalogue Index of Samuel Bourne's Indian Photographs.)
    Original negative number: 1132B
  - A Group of H. E. the Viceroy's Elephants with their State Trappings, circa 1865-1866; 8 3/4 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 1, Print RL-00130-P-1132D)
    From Photograph Album 1: Farther India, page 37. Studio number not present on print; verified through studio list and captioned prints in other collections.
    Original negative number: 1132D
  - Subathoo from the Barracks, looking West, circa 1865-1866; 8 3/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 14, Print RL-00130-P-1133)
    Original negative number: 1133
  - Subathoo, looking towards the Barracks, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1134)
    Original negative number: 1134
  - Sanawur; from the Church, looking towards the Play-ground, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1138)
    Image is of boys' asylum and school.
    Original negative number: 1138
  - Sanawur; Girls at play in front of School, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1141)
    Original negative number: 1141